<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About me on Patrick's Homepage</title><link>http://localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content in About me on Patrick's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.1</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 20:36:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rediscovered my GPG Key</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpgkeys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 20:36:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gpgkeys/</guid><description>After some task at work I remembered that I once created a GPG Key during a information security class. So I started to search for it and found it on my old windows machine with this command
gpg --list-keys So I wondered if I can export this key and reuse it. Google as always had an answer for me!
Private GPG Keys are protected by a passphrase which is choosen when generating a keypair.</description></item><item><title>Glossary webpage with yaml and mdBook</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mdbookglossary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mdbookglossary/</guid><description>Introduction Today I finished my work on a glossary page. My goal was to have a single source of truth, for wording which is used in my company and definition and translations to it.
So I decided to use a *.yaml file to save source strings of the wordings, definitions and their translations. I made a basic iterable structure with key/value pairs for the term, an abstract and a description. See the following example to get a notion:</description></item><item><title>My first experiences with devcontainers</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/devcontainers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:39:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/devcontainers/</guid><description>After an update of Visual Studio Code in my workplace, I encountered an added functionality: Devcontainers. So I decided to read into the topic. This lead to solving some problems in my workplace, which were unconformable to work with until now, but weren&amp;rsquo;t also that bad to start finding another solution for them.
Let&amp;rsquo;s begin at the start of the story:
What are development containers? Development containers are, as the name suggests, containers which have the purpose to unify development experience.</description></item><item><title>First Hugo Homepage</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 11:51:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first/</guid><description>My first real project with Hugo is this website.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to create a over complexified project as a first thing with hugo so I decided to finally make a homepage for myself with it.</description></item><item><title>Haus Einsiedler</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/haus-einsiedler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/haus-einsiedler/</guid><description>One of my first websites, had been a information page for my grandma&amp;rsquo;s holiday apartment.
The website is based on Joomla but with a custom template. By the way it was the first Joomla template which I wrote.
Here you can visit the page: Haus Einsiedler</description></item></channel></rss>